<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the bottom line</title>
    <description>A marketing and design agency which exsists to pursue the sole aim of positively impacting your businesses bottom line by creating simple solutions which showcase your individuality and helps you attract, grow, and engage with your customers
</description>
    <link>http://bottomline.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bottomline.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 19:09:15 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 19:09:15 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>James Dyson and the Creative Process</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his latest, hugely insightful book, Mathew Syed investigates the role of failure in success, and why some people are able to recognise and learn from their mistakes whilst discussing the cognitive biases that stop others from doing the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend this book, it’s not a typical ‘we should fail really often’ narrative you’ve probably heard often, but rather an in depth insightful look at the culture and attitudes towards failure in industries and individuals. It’s well researched and well written. The main contrast that runs through the entirety of the book is the subtle but impactful differences between the aviation industry and the medical industry, and why the aviation industry is a pioneering one when it comes to embracing and learning from failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, one of the most insightful pieces in the book, was an interview conducted by Mathew with James Dyson. James is truly a pioneer, his foundation is dedicated to “enouraging young people to think different, make mistakes, invent and realise their engienering potential”. Most people know him as the guy who owns Dyson who make hoovers and hand dryers; but very few know the story behind his innovations and success. It’s safe to say he is a true innovator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has been championing the role of creativity in Engineering for many years now and in this book he breaks it down for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People think of creativity as a mystical process. The idea is that creative insights emerge from the ether through pure contemplation. This model conceives of innovation as something that happens to people, normally geniuses. But this could not be more wrong. Creativity is something that has to be worked at, and it has specific characteristics. Unless we understand how it happens, we will not improve our creativity, as a society or as a world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does creativity happen and how can we be more creative? Mathew goes on to describe the role of failure and contradictory information in jaring the door to progress and new solutions. He describes how we are able to think beyond our usual thought processes when our ideas are challenged. Without conflict, our thinking will never change. We would have no reason to do anything in any different way then the ways that our minds are programmed to recognise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The creative process started with a problem, what you might even call a failure, in the existing technology. The vacuum cleaner kept blocking. It let out a screaming noise. Dyson had to keep bending down to pick up bits of rubbish by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Had everything gone smoothly Dyson would have had no motivation to change things. Moreover, he would have had no intellectual challenge to sink his teeth into. It was the very nature of the engineering problem that sparked a possible solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And this turns out to be the most perfect metaphor for the creative process, whether it involves vacuum cleaners, a quest for a new brand name or a new scientific theory. Creativity is, in many respects, a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that without recognising a failure, and without recognising that our present solution is far from optimal we have absolutely no reason to stray from our usual thinking and to activate our minds in search of a solution. We carry on doing things the same way because perhaps we don’t recognise the problem; perhaps we don’t deem it worthy of our attention; or perhaps we don’t recognise that a better solution is available. That is why we must as engineers begin to question the way we work, and allow conflict and contradiction to surround us. That is why we at Engineering Minds advocate the broadening of horizons. When you learn about different industries, you learn about solutions to problems and how they are overcome, and you begin to draw parallels, and the result is that your worldview expands. When your worldview expands, your understanding of problems and solutions changes entirely. You are no longer confined into one space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-we-as-business-owners-actively-challenged-in-the-way-we-doing-things-enough&quot;&gt;Are we as business owners, actively challenged in the way we doing things enough?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking beyond major innovations and examples of creativty, there are processes and solutions we use ever day that are far from optimal, but these are rarely challenged, and the result is a sort of plodding along, doing the same things in the same way without much insight or challenge as to the effectiveness of the eventual outcome. Sometimes the outcome itself isn’t necessary but we don’t realise it becuase it’s a process we’ve been carrying out for year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativity doesn’t need to be a magnificent new solution to a problem. Creativity could be as simple as the merging of two processes into one more effective solution that saves times, and achieves a better outcome. That is after all, exactly the same creativity that Dyson was able to apply in his innovation, in 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was a connecting agent. The act of creativity was an act, above all, of synthesis. … In his moment of insight he essentially brought together two disparate ideas together: a vacuum and a sawmill. It turns out that this act of connectivity is another central feature of innovation.
Back to our businesses, so what can we do to reintroduce creativity into our work? (Each of these points will eventually warrant a blog post in themselves)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expand-your-worldview&quot;&gt;1. Expand your worldview.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your worldview is the way you see things and the bigger our worldview the more insight we are able to take from events. A wider worldview means we can recognise failures in one industry, by looking to another and understanding how they have overcome a very similar problem. We are able to merge ideas, and bring together two seemingly unrelated ideas and allow them to transpire into the solution we require.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embrace-contradiction-failure-and-conflict&quot;&gt;2. Embrace contradiction, failure and conflict.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure is useful in two area essential to progress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is useful as an igniting spark for creativity.
Without these we have no reason to change and things will continue to progress as they have been. Do we really want that? Failure is the catalyst to change
It is useful in the execution phase that takes our creativity and turns it into an optimum solution. 
Back to Dyson on why we’re only 2 percent of the way there now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is no good creating the most beautiful products if you produce them shoddily it is no good having the most innovative engineering solution if the customers can be certain it will be delivered on time. It is no good if inconsistent production means that a great idea is not translated into a finished product. The original idea is only 2 per cent of the journey. You mustn’t neglect the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dyson reveals the secrets behind his innovations and how discipline allowed him to continuously learn from failure and iterate on his designs hundreds of times until he was comfortable with a finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dyson was not the first to come up with the idea of a cyclone vacuum cleaner. He was not even the second, or the third. But he was the only one with the stamina to ‘fail’ his concept into a workable solution. And he had the rigour to create an efficient manufacturing process, so he could sell a consistent product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took dyson 5127 iterations to reach the optimal solution for his bagless vacuum cleaner. 5127! Embracing failure not only allows us to ignite the creative process, it allows us to reach optimum solutions to problems. More on the role of failure in reaching optimum solutions in, for now lets return to how we can be more creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;examine-your-ideas-often&quot;&gt;3. Examine your Ideas Often.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand from the Dyson story that creativity didn’t happen in a brainstorming session. Creativity occured becuase Dyson had the intuition to examine what was an everyday object, whilst refusing to accept that it was optimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He embraced the problem. Most people would just accept that the hoover was rubbish and deal with all of it’s associated problems.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He had the worldview to find a solution. A hoover and a sawmill. He understood both seemingly unrelated objects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He asked questions, he surrounded himself with contradictory information and information that would allow him to expand on the initial idea.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The role of an effective engineering culture then isn’t to facillitate change as a temporary process but as an integral part of the way work is done. Only by allowing people to examine and question the way things are done at all times, will we being to recognise problems and arrive at solutions. Discussion, contradiction and conflict in our work as engineers allow us to move forwards.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book Tribes, Seth Godin describes why those who should encourage non-sheep behaviour and the constant examining of the way things are done. The biggest step, though, comes from anyone who teaches or hires. And that’s to embrace non-sheep behavior, to reward it and cherish it. As we’ve seen just about everywhere there’s been growth lately, that’s where the good stuff happens
Understand and Seek Creativity in Your Everyday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the next couple of weeks, think about James Dyson and the creative process. Take some time to think about the things that really irk you in your work (I guess a lot). Talk about them, talk to people that don’t do what you do, let them ask questions. You’d be surprised at how many issues you’ve just come to accept and some of the simple solutions that can begin to appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at bottom line, we don’t promise quick solutions but we do promise thoughtful and purposeful solutions which are tailored specifically to your needs. We allow ourselves the time to let things stew and improve upon them throughout the project, all within a fixed fee structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bottomline.io/marketing/2016/10/10/dyson-creativity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bottomline.io/marketing/2016/10/10/dyson-creativity.html</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Re-embracing the Act of Creating</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time we all re-embraced the act of creating. It’s why the majority of us are where we are. We grew up creating, solving problems in the way of games and puzzles. Somewhere along the way, and we have all been guilty of this, we revert to a more traditional constrained style of thinking that doesn’t allow us to create. We do too much exploitation of the things that exist in our current world view, and not enough exploration of what else is possible. This may have been possible 10 years ago but the speed t which technology is developed these days means that you’re constantly under threat if you don’t place yourself in a position where you can adapt and change to your environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a business owner, it can be easy to fall into this trap with the every day pressures and deadlines it may feel like you don’t have the lucury to explore or create. We deal exclusively with the impending, with what we currently have, with facts, numbers and figures. I believe this is something that is engrained over time as opposed to a natural trait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very practice of creating, and creating often, gets one into the habit of thinking creatively and looking for solutions out with the ordinary or accepted. Creating can be anything, it’s not important, but its the habit of thinking and doing which&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the below video by Stef Lewandowski who’s mantra is “Create something every day”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A rule:
I live by the rule “create something every day”, which means I’ve become good at hacking things together quickly using code and design. The term “hacker” was given to me because I’ve done so many little hack projects. The thing is, that one or two of them have turned into real live businesses…&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;
Stef is primarily a techie but the mantra and principles are useful for anyone, especially engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/103193667&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what lessons can we draw from this video?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter what you create, just create.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Engrain it in your routine. Get into the habit and you’ll no longer think of it as creating. It’s hard at the start, but the habit of creating becomes natural and engrained in your day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There’s so many different ways you can create. Write. Speak. Add value to something.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Creativity can be developed - and you should actively seek to develop your creativity as an engineer. Creativity isn’t just about design, it’s about solving problems in an innovative way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You should actively seek to develop a creative mindset as an engineer, it’ll help you design and engineer better solutions. It’ll allow you to tap into your ideas and thoughts more fully. You’ll be able to think about processes and ideas differently within your role. The benefits are multiple.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should never stop creating. If creating something every day seems like a stretch, then start by creating something every week. Actively pursue unusual solutions to everyday problems, if design isn’t your thing, think about the process and the way things are built. You’ll be surprised at some of the things you’ll discover when you start questioning things that have become accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minute a busienss stops creating and gets comfortable, this is when creativity begins to flounder and accepted solutions become commonplace. Lack of exploration, can be detrimental to your busines and is the enemy of your abilities to become a proactive and creative leader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bottomline.io/design/2016/10/03/reembrace-creating.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bottomline.io/design/2016/10/03/reembrace-creating.html</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Power of Story Telling</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A story takes all the senseless data that the world provides and turns it into something meaningful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories spread faster than corporate copy-write or in your face marketing materials, they alleviate doubt and simplify even the complex into something uniquely relatable. Whatever your business does, in whatever function or level you should think about this and how it can make an impact in the way that you communicate your ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst our desire to solve problems for our customer we forget the stories that actually make our work meaningful and exciting. We’re too engrained in the numbers, the details, the charts, when often a simple story would be far more worthwhile. Our brains are able to cope with and retain narrative context in a far better way than facts and figures, and it’s time we used this to our advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a better way to present your solution, then throwing up as many facts and figures as possible on a powerpoint and hope for the best. Even if you’re read up on the art of presenting effectively, there’s still a chance you’re presentation is missing something without the use of a narrative to communicate your key points. This is even more prevalent when you consider the interactions that we have to make as business owners on a day to day basis. We are always telling stories to our coworkers and employees in an effort to persuade them or provide a solution or to seek change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is though, it’s hard. Really hard. Some subjects and settings just don’t lend themselves to amazing presentations, and powerful story telling. But it is possible, I assure you. It takes time though - time and careful thought - to develop your own story telling style. But it’s worthwhile, because stories create emotions that allow our ideas to stick and move forwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good stories have the power to unify a team and create a common goal to strive for. Story telling can be made up of real experiences or a craft of narratives twisted around the facts. I’m not suggesting you should tell fairytales or lies to make your point exciting, but I’m suggesting drawing parallels and using common language and narrative to craft your solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story telling is just as basic as you when you were taught it in primary school. You use plot, characters, and turning point/surprise/ or dramatic twist of some sort. It’s not changed since then, the same principles apply, even in engineering. The only thing that changes is the context, the villain of your story could be that really complex problem you’ve been working tirelessly to overcome. Whilst working on this problem you undoubtedly had to make changes, and had to react to failures along the way. Maybe you found your solution in a surprising place? How did you find the solution, and how does it help you move forward? What’s the happy ending?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where do we start? From the beginning. Whats the purpose of your work? Think about the why of what you’re doing and make it relatable. You might have heard of the example about the man approaching bricklayers on the construction site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A man came upon a construction site where three people were working.  He asked the first, “What are you doing?” and the man replied: “I am laying bricks.” He asked the second, “What are you doing?” and the man replied: “I am building a wall.” As he approached the third, he heard him humming a tune as he worked, and asked, “What are you doing?” The man stood, looked up at the sky, and smiled, “I am building a cathedral!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That man, was doing exactly the same thing as his colleagues but he understood two things, the power of having a powerful greater purpose, and the power of story telling. What can we learn from our cathedral building friend?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He can see the big picture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He knows the why of what he is doing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How knows how what he is doing fits into his organisations goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets build on this example and examine how even the seaminlgy complex can capture people’s attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note when describing this example, I build upon the following article describing how Elon pitches and what we can learn from it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this pitch, Elon is essentially telling a story and there are two parts that hold the secret to why it is such an effective delivery: the traits and characteristics he displays; and the way in which he structures his narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;delivering-his-narrative&quot;&gt;Delivering his Narrative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine the way the traits in which he delivers his message. The important thing to note here is that we are discussing the way he comes across as opposed to critiquing his delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He’s Passionate and Shows Emotion&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;He’s absolutely fascinated and convinced by the story and the solution he is presenting. He’s massivley engrossed in everything that he is doing and this is pretty clear to the audience. It’s very hard to fake this, so we need convey a passion in what we do in order to tell stories well. We then need to share our passions with the audience and be able to convey our enthusiasm and excitement so that the audience can connect with you and share your passions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He Considers his Audience (How does this fit into my audiences goals?)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Elon knows he’s pitching to people from a variety of backgrounds so he considerately avoids the use of Jargon. He estimated his audiences ability to understand the presentation and also what they were looking to gain from the story. He choose a framework that would resonate with them.  He couples this by knowing the most important points that he wants his audience to take away: these problems exist and we should care; Tesla are solving them; this is how tesla are solving them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He Uses Words Suitable for Non Tehnical People (Is this suitable for my audience?)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is one technical people are often guilty of - turning up to a client pitch and going into full flow about which CMS you prefer and why. Or perhaps turning up to a meeting with various departments and neglecting the backgrounds of the audience mebers entirely. Explaining things non technically does two things, it increases your knowledge of the subject and allows your audience to follow the story more readily.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He knows the subject (How does my solution aleviate the problem?)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;He has an in depth understanding of the subject that is clear but at no point does he overwhelm his audience with it. More on how Elon Achieves his in depth understanding of subjects . But the important thing here is that he knows the history, and the details of his subject matter. His audience have no doubts about his relative understanding of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He makes it about People (How can I stir emotion and create action)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Stories are about people and so they must play an important role throughout. The solution that Musk presents is about people, a bettter world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;structuring-the-narrative&quot;&gt;Structuring the Narrative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets look at the way Elon structures his narrative. It’s well thought out and captures the attention of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He Presents the Big Picture First&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Just like our cathedral building friend, he presents the big picture. He avoids unnecessary detail and instead captivates the audience in his narrative by making an extremely complex issue seem imminintely solveable by breaking it down into manageable pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He names the villian (Why we must take action)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;As in the stories we were told when we were younger, Elons narrative has a clear Villian who we absolutely must overcome. In the blog post linked above the writer says:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;When Musk shows this image of burning fossil fuels, you can practically hear Darth Vader’s ominous breath.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He uses a pattern of tension and resolution (Stirring more emotion)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;He builds anticipation throughout by first showing us that this extremely complex issue (the villian) is imminently solveable (defeatable) if we apply the correct resources, and if we act soon.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Before saying anything about batteries, Musk describes his version of happily-ever-after: a civilization powered by “this handy fusion reactor in the sky, called the Sun.” Showing the enemy’s defeat before explaining how you’ll make it happen can feel wrong for novice presenters — like blurting out the punchline before you’ve told a joke. But when an audience knows where you’re headed, they’re much more likely to buckle in for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He Tells Us About the Struggles&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Having broke down the problem and made us feel it is imminintely soleable, he know tells us about the struggles and barriers to success.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Musk addresses three obstacles to a solar-powered world:
 (i) The amount of energy produced by solar panels varies throughout the day and night (thus the need for batteries):
 (ii) Most people think the land area required for batteries to store enough energy to rid U.S. of fossil fuels would be really huge (but according to Musk, it’s that tiny red dot in Texas):
 (iii) Currently available batteries suck in seven specific ways&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Resolution (And How it Will it Defeat the Villian)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Having told us about the the big picture, the villian, the solution, and the struggles, he then presents the resolution to his story - The Powerwall. In another twist he provides evidence by revealing the Powerwall batteries are supplying the auditorium form which he is speaking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-can-we-create-better-stories&quot;&gt;So how can we create better stories?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to be more aware of the factors listed above, but also to begin to conciously examine our experiences in search of effective narratives that will convey our message better. People reosnate with experienes and emotions and so this is absolutely critical to story telling. Think of your friends or colleagues who are the most jovial and best story tellers you know, it’s often the way that they convey the emotion that sets their stories apart. Not the content itself. So we need find the events in our lives that have shaped the ideas we are conveying. These anecdotes are an integral part of conveying our message and beginning to appreicate them and consider them as either a tool when we protray our ideas or as the emodyment of the idea in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to begin story telling more effectively, We need to start mining your personal experiencess for stories that support your ideas and begin dripping them into the way you present your solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bottomline.io/marketing/2016/09/26/the-power-of-story-telling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bottomline.io/marketing/2016/09/26/the-power-of-story-telling.html</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
